Contact

G-11/1, Islamabad Pakistan 03161223590 (Mobile) m.walidaslam@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/waleedaslam (LinkedIn) github.com/walidaslam7 (Other)

Top Skills
ASP.NET MVC
ASP.NET Core
MSSQL

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Urdu (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards
Speed Coding Competition

Waleed Aslam

AZURE | .NET CORE | ASP.NET MVC | SQL & NOSQL Islāmābād

Summary

4+ years of professional experience as a Full Stack .Net Developer, Experience in SDLC which includes Analysis, Requirements, Design, Development, Testing, Maintenance of web-based apps. Practices and knowledge in developing web applications using .Net Framework/.Net Core, ASP.Net MVC Arch, N-tier, DI based Arch, Web-APIs, Azure DevOps, Azure Functions/SDKs, Azure Storages like Table-API & Queues, Razor, HTML, CSS, Ajax, Jquery, MS-SQL, Cosmos Db.

Experience

Synergy-IT Pakistan Software Engineer June 2020 - Present (1 year 4 months) Islāmābād, Pakistan

e-strats

2 years 7 months

Development Team Lead February 2019 - May 2020 (1 year 4 months) Islāmābād. Pakistan

Designated as a team lead to supervise my team members and coordinate with them for better results.

Currently working in Agile & Sprints methodology for development and testing activities that are concurrent, It also encourages teamwork and face-to-face communication.

Technologies/Frameworks Used:

- C#, ASP.NET MVC, .NET CORE,
- · Web Forms and Desktop Apps
- React, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON and AJAX
- HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3 and Bootstrap
- Entity Framework, ADO.NET and LINQ

- SQL Server, Cosmos DB and T-SQL
- REST and SOAP Web APIs
- · Microsoft Azure deployment and MS Repos
- Telerik/Kendo UI for ASP.NET MVC
- Google Maps API, RTR and Intuit Quick Books API
- Team Foundation Server, GIT, DevOps, JIRA, Trello, and Air table
- Microsoft IIS Application Server and Application Deployment
- Payments Gateways like Blue Pay, Authorize.net and Stripe

Software Engineer

November 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Pakistan

- Coding, maintaining and updating software development solutions
- · Learning and implementing new technical concepts
- Responsible to create a new application from Scratch and Support/modify in Existing

Projects Technologies/Frameworks Used: ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core, MSSQL Server, HTML, JavaScript/jQuery

Exalted Software Solutions Software Engineer July 2017 - November 2017 (5 months) Islāmābād. Pakistan

EmCentrix Software Engineer August 2016 - July 2017 (1 year)

Islāmābād, Pakistan

- Design, develop and testing of web application in ASP.NET.
- Coordinate with the Team Lead on current programming tasks.
- Maintaining complete and up to date documentation of all office work.
- Continuously learn and improve skills

Gomal University
Computer Specialist
May 2016 - June 2017 (1 year 2 months)
Dera ismail Khan

Education

Qurtuba University of Science and Technology Master's degree, Computer Science · (2013 - 2016)

Gomal University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2011 - 2013)

KANZ College

Faculty of Science, Engineering · (2009 - 2011)